John Emmanuel A. Galang

+63 956 879 8747 Imman.galang@gmail.com LinkedIn Online Portfolio

Front-end Web Developer

A front-end web developer based in the Philippines experienced in creating and maintaining stylish and responsive websites. Proficient in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript; plus modern frameworks and libraries. While I have spent the last few years developing my writing, researching, and designing skills as a researcher and freelancer, I believe my background will bring valuable perspective.

Highlights of Expertise

- Front-End Development
- Bootstrap
- Adobe Photoshop
- Attention to Detail
- Highly Organized

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- SASS
- Git Version Control
- Communication and Collaboration
- Analytical and Technical Problem Solving

Education & Credentials

University of the Philippines Los Baños, 2015-2019

BS Agricultural Biotechnology

Zuitt Coding Bootcamp, 2021-Present

Front-end, Back-end, and Full-stack Development

Career Experience

Freelancer

VIDEO EDITOR AND GRAPHIC DESIGNER (July 2021 to Present)

Creates videos from shooting to final upload. Shoot own A-roll and B-roll clips. Video edit using Adobe Premiere Pro and create thumbnails using Adobe Photoshop. Write titles, video descriptions, and tags that are optimized for SEO.

- Monetized my own YouTube channel and reached 150,000 views on my YouTube Channel.
- From 0 to 1500 Subscribers in less than a year.
- Repurpose videos from Youtube to other platforms like Instagram and Tiktok.

University of the Philippines – Los Baños, Laguna

UNIVERSITY RESEARCH ASSOCIATE (July 2020 to July 2021)

Organizes and maintains database related to project activities and findings. Ensures accuracy by verifying data which entails comparing reports to raw data to reduce errors and make sure that all information is up to date and as complete as possible.

 Directs a team of laboratory technicians in developing an alternative method of propagating bamboo species.

- Oversees various research experiments simultaneously and ensures adherence to protocol and time frame.
- Monitors administrative work that ranges from procurement of items, recruitment of project staff, to writing progress reports.
- Analyses and interprets data in excel sheets on all research experiments conducted and presents them to the project leader.

Philchema, Inc., Quezon City

TECHNICAL STAFF (Nov 2019 to June 2020)

Created and administered enhanced production testing of prototypes. Presented production and process data and information and trends reports to management through meticulous collection analysis and thorough summary.

- Assisted the technical team comprised of animal nutritionists and R&D specialists in conducting trials, experiments, and gathering data to further boost the company's sales and credibility of the company's products.
- Provided support to the sales team including area managers and district managers by organizing files of
 each company product which involved certificates of analysis, specification sheets, brochures, and fliers
 to be made readily available for them.
- Conducted research on updates, trends, product survey, and industry issues and presented analysis of its effects in the industry in general, and to the company.
- Managed all equipment troubleshooting and system optimization tasks at the laboratory to keep the technical services efficient and optimized.

Trainings and Certifications

Licensed Professional Agriculturist (Feb 2020-Apr 2023) | Professional Regulation Commission,
 Philippines